

# **CHARLIE BEAVERS**

Address: 7 Birch Ave, Thornton-Cleveleys, FY5 2HT

Phone: 07850 601513

Email: foxhall3@hotmail.com

Experienced and motivated eCommerce expert seeking a new challenge in this everchanging market. I am currently in my second year of a Computer Science degree and have worked as a website manager for over two years. I've designed, built, and maintained a variety of websites, each with my own unique flair.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **ECOMMERCE MANAGER** (2022 - PRESENT)

#### SOUTH PLANKS LTD / STONE UK LTD

- Management of 2 eCommerce websites and overseeing the development of 2 web projects
- Head of online marketing through Mailchimp, social media, Google platforms, and more
- Fast paced role undertaking a several tasks different task each day
- Management of sales through eBay, Amazon, Etsy & Facebook Marketplace
- Coordinating tasks with other freelance professionals

**REASON FOR LEAVING:** Limited resources

### **ECOMMERCE MANAGER** (2019 - 2022)

### SECOND CHANCE LTD

- Management of 6 eCommerce websites, eBay store and companies wholesale website
- Developed multilingual websites able to ship products worldwide.
- Responsible for Google platform marketing and growing sales through campaigns.
- Reporting on ROI, conversion rates, traffic, etc. to the director and acting upon new ideas.
- Working with a small team to build brands, grow sales and keep up with market trends.

**REASON FOR LEAVING:** Presented a better offer

## **SKILLS**

eCommerce Websites

HTML & CSS

**MAGENTO** 

JAVASCRIPT

PHP

## **EDUCATION**

Open University (2021 - Present)

BSc (Honours) Computing and IT (Software)

University of Birmingham (2010 / 13)

FdSc (Foundation) Professional Golf Studies

Lytham St Anne's Sixth Form (2004 / 05)

AS Level - Information Technology

AS Level - Sport Studies

AS Level - Biology

### Highfield High School (1999 / 04)

GCSE - English, Mathematics, Science, Information Technology, Physical Education, Geography, and Religious Studies.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### FREELANCE (2019 - PRESENT)

#### WEB DEVELOPER

- Developing websites for small businesses
- Managing websites for small businesses
- Still working closely with Second Chance Ltd
- Creating marketing assets
- Server side maintenance
- Maintaining personal eCommerce websites

**REASON FOR LEAVING:** If the position requires my whole focus, I am happy to stop.

### PGA Professional (2010 - 2019)

#### VARIES ESTABLISHMENTS

- Well established Golf Professional creating my very own successful coaching business
- Created my first eCommerce website selling one to one coaching and online golf lessons
- Created and launched a successful junior golf coaching programme
- Contracted to work in golf retail shop and online sales
- Competing in professional golf tournaments

**REASON FOR LEAVING: Covid** 

### **OTHER EMPLOYMENT** (2005 - 2013)

MARKETING EXECUTIVE - PERTH, AUSTRALIA

SHIFT MANAGER - DOMINO'S PIZZA

ASSISTANT MANAGER - GOLF CLUB BAR

NIGHT PORTER - WARWICK HOTEL

## **CERTIFICATES**

### Cisco Networking Academy

• Networking Essentials

### Distance Learning Centre

- Webmaster JavaScript level 4
- Webmaster Responsive Web Design level. 4
- Webmaster HTML & CSS level 3

#### Treehouse.com

• Front-end Web Development

#### LinkedIn Learning

- Excel 2019 Essential Training
- Social Media Marketing
- Photo Editing Essential Training

## **GENERAL SKILLS**

- Magento, WordPress, WooCommerce & Shopify
- Facebook, Instagram, LinkedIn & TikTok
- ERP Software & Order Management Software,
- Graphic Design with Canva & Figma
- Facilities to work from home
- Reliable and happy to commute
- Clean UK driving licence

## **INTERESTS**

Avid user of all things digital, with a passion for website and software development. I also manage a busy working calendar while playing in professional golf tournaments, and continuing to learning about programme languages and artificial intelligence.

## <u>REFERENCES</u>

## Stone UK Ltd

David Evans (Director)

Email: david@stoneuk.com Call: 01995 600551

## **REFERENCES**

Second Chance Ltd

Chris Preston (Manager)

Email: chrispreston@secondchance.co.uk Call: 01253 407272

HAPPY FOR YOU TO CONTACT

PLEASE ASK BEFORE CONTACTING